Forever is just the beginning.
The Twilight Saga: Breaking Dawn - Part 1 is a adventure,
fantasy, romance film directed by Bill Condon.
Bella Swan and Edward Cullen's honeymoon phase is abruptly disrupted by
betrayals and unforeseen tragedies that endanger their world.
Bella Swan, played by Kristen Stewart.
Edward Cullen, played by Robert Pattinson.
Jacob Black, played by Taylor Lautner.
Charlie Swan, played by Billy Burke.
Dr. Carlisle Cullen, played by Peter Facinelli.
Aro, played by Michael Sheen.
The Twilight Saga: Breaking Dawn – Part 1 is a 2011 American vampire romantic fantasy film directed by Bill Condon
from a screenplay by Melissa Rosenberg, based on the 2008 novel Breaking Dawn by Stephenie Meyer.
It is the sequel to The Twilight Saga: Eclipse (2010) and the
fourth installment in The Twilight Saga film series.
The film stars Kristen Stewart, Robert Pattinson, and Taylor Lautner, reprising their
roles as Bella Swan, Edward Cullen, and Jacob Black, respectively.
In the film, Bella and Edward marry and become pregnant with a half-human, half-vampire child,
which causes the Cullen family to become a target of Jacob and his Wolf Pack.
Summit Entertainment announced that Breaking Dawn would be
adapted into a two-part film on June 10, 2010.
Principal photography for both parts began on November
1, 2010, and wrapped on April 22, 2011.
The first part was shot in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Baton
Rouge, Louisiana; and Vancouver, Canada.
The Twilight Saga: Breaking Dawn – Part 1 premiered at the Rome Film Festival on October 30, 2011, and
was theatrically released in the United States on November 18, by Summit Entertainment.
The film received mixed to unfavorable reviews from critics with criticism aimed at pacing, screenplay and
performances, but grossed $732 million worldwide, becoming the fourth-highest-grossing film of 2011.
A sequel, Breaking Dawn – Part 2, was released in 2012.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
vampire, hybrid, teen movie, werewolf.
The tone is emotional.